Guide to the United Automobile Workers of America, Local 2110 Records WAG.188
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
United Automobile Workers of America, Local 2110 Records
1942-2026, ongoing
1942-2004
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
International Union, United Automobile, Aerospace, and Agricultural Implement Workers of America. Local 2110 (New York, N.Y.)
Rosenstein, Maida
WAG.188
5.5 Linear Feet in 4 record cartons and 3 manuscript boxes
24 websites in 24 archived websites.
The Technical, Office and Professional (TOP) Union, Local 2110, is an amalgamated union with over 30 contracts covering workers in universities, publishing, museums, law firms and other offices. They represent teachers, secretaries, administrators, editors, computer operators, librarians, museum curators, typesetters and graphic artists, and other workers. The records of UAW 2110 consist of contracts and agreements between organizations and their employees, pamphlets and brochures, correspondence including emails, shop files, reports, financial material, archived websites, and VHS tapes.
Related Archival Materials
United Automobile Workers (UAW), Local 2110: Adjunct and Graduate Students Organizing Records. (WAG 285)
United Automobile Workers of America, District 65 Oral History Collection (OH 19)
United Automobile Workers of America, District 65 Photographs — Part I Negatives. (PHOTOS 023)
United Automobile Workers of America, District 65 Records. (WAG 006)
Yale Graduate Student Union Records (TAM 233)
Arrangement
The collection is divided into two series:
Series I: Papers and Audiovisual Materials
Series II: Archived Websites
Folders are generally arranged chronologically.
Scope and Contents
United Automobile Workers of America, Local 2110 Records consist of contracts and agreements between organizations and their employees, pamphlets and brochures, correspondence including emails, shop files, reports, financial material, archived websites, and VHS tapes. The UAW 2110 records reflect their affiliations with a variety of institutional associations. The Brooklyn Historical Society, Long Island Historical Society, National Law Journal, Royal Business School and Riverside Church are among them. Club Med, the vacation company, the Silent Watchman, a home alarm company, and the Glemby Corporation, which in the 1990s was the nation's largest department store hair salon chain, all had distinct subseries in the collection. Glemby Corporation records include occupational safety surveys, as well as negotiations and employee claims. The Silent Watchman negotiations concern the United Wholesale and Warehouse Employees. The records related to District 65 are primarily financial, but also include an election, general information and a Black Lake retreat. The time period covered is from 1980-1989.
In 2002, NYU's teaching, research and graduate assistants won major economic gains and a first-ever union contract with UAW 2110. In 2004 the National Labor Relations Board (NLRB) overturned the decision. There are also some emails related to when NYU which was officially part of UAW 2110 from 2000-2004.
Historical Note
The Technical, Office and Professional (TOP) Union, Local 2110, is an amalgamated union with 30 contracts covering over 3,000 workers in universities, publishing, museums, law firms and other offices. They represent teachers, secretaries, administrators, editors, computer operators, librarians, museum curators, typesetters and graphic artists, among many others. The union claims that they've taken the lead in organizing women and workers in non-profits who never had been organized before. They have won benefits such as childcare, flex-time, job classification, domestic partner benefits and family leave and organize and negotiate for "white collar" workers. Their area of representation includes New England, Washington D.C., New York metropolitan area, and Puerto Rico. Some organizations they work with are:
Addison—Wesley Longman Publishers
Ames & Rollinson
AMSCO School Publications
Barnard College
Bronx Museum of the Arts
Church World Service
Columbia University
DASNY: Dormitory Authority of the State of New York
Feminist Press
GOLES: Good Old Lower East Side
HarperCollins Publishers
HFA: New York State Housing Finance Agency
ICCR: Interfaith Center on Corporate Responsibility
Mercy College
Monthly Review
Museum of Modern Art, New York
National Council of Churches
New Press
NYANA: New York Association for New Americans
New York Civil Liberties Union
New—York Historical Society
Rabinowitz, Boudin, Standard, Krinsky & Lieberman, P.C.
SONYMA: State of New York Mortgage Agency
Stamford Advocate
State Bank of India
TCI: Technical Careers Institute
Teachers College
Union Theological Seminary
Village Voice
District 65 traces its origins to the Wholesale Dry Goods Workers Union and New York's Lower East Side. It was one of many unions formed during the early years of the Great Depression. For a considerable period its membership consisted of primarily Jewish garment workers. The Union has a progressive and politically active history. It stood against McCarthyism during the virulent anti-communist, red scare era and stood against the Vietnam War decades later. In 1992, District 65 merged with Local 2110. Local 2110 acquired the records of former bargaining units, including academic records primarily addressing organizing campaigns at Yale and Boston University. The Historical Societies, Church Organizations, and Misc are primarily former bargaining units of D 65.
Some organizing campaigns include: the Lower East Side Tenement Museum, New York University Graduate Student Organizing Committee, Columbia University Teaching and Research Assistants (GSEU), the Hispanic Society, the Guggenheim, Brooklyn Academy of Music, Film Forum, the Brooklyn Museum, the Whitney Museum, and the American Folk Museum. Local 2110 is actively involved in ongoing struggles to unionize each of these institutions.
Some of the issues UAW 2110 advocates for are healthcare reform, the rights of employees when faced with intimidation by employers for participating in Union activities, and bargaining rights.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Maida Rosenstein, President of the United Automobile Workers, Local 2110, in 1999. The accession number associated with this gift is 1999.024.
https://www.2110uaw.org/ was initially selected by curators and captured through the use of The California Digital Library's Web Archiving Service in 2009 as part of the Labor Unions and Organizations (U.S.) Web Archive. In 2015, this website was migrated to Archive-It. Archive-It uses web crawling technology to capture websites at a scheduled time and displays only an archived copy, from the resulting WARC file, of the website. In January 2023, https://linktr.ee/hcpunion/ and https://twitter.com/hcpunion/ were added. The accession number associated with these websites is 2023.007. In March 2023, https://www.filmforumunion.org/ was added. The accession number associated with this website is 2023.029. In April 2023, http://brooklynmuseumunion.org/, http://guggenheimmuseumunion.org/, https://taunion.org/, http://studioinaschoolunion.org/, http://mainepmaunion.org/, https://bfsunion.org/, https://www.bamunion.org/, and https://drive.google.com/file/d/1FV_5FAJsHkbj-Sh1eFyVwQFy_V6uAibv/view were added. The accession number associated with these websites is 2023.043. In May 2023, https://www.facebook.com/people/UAW-Local-2110/100063493332901/, https://linktr.ee/hispanicsocietyunion/, and http://whitneymuseumunion.org/ were added. The accession number associated with these websites is 2023.046. In June 2024, https://www.instagram.com/afam_union/ was added. The accession number associated with this website is 2024.040. In July 2024, http://flcunion.org/ and http://www.massmocaunion.org/ were added. The accession number associated with these websites are 2024.041. In October 2024, https://x.com/hcpunion/ was added. The accession number associated with this website is 2024.056. In Spring 2025, https://www.instagram.com/noguchiunion/ and https://linktr.ee/abramsunion/ were added. The accession number associated with these websites is 2025.039. In late 2025, https://metunion.org/, https://www.instagram.com/metunion/, and https://linktr.ee/metunion/ were added. The accession number associated with these websites 2026.022.
Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures
Audiovisual materials have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers. Materials not yet digitized will need to have access copies made before they can be used. To request an access copy, or if you are unsure if an item has been digitized, please contact special.collections@nyu.edu with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.
Take Down Policy
Archived websites are made accessible for purposes of education and research. NYU Libraries have given attribution to rights holders when possible; however, due to the nature of archival collections, we are not always able to identify this information.
If you hold the rights to materials in our archived websites that are unattributed, please let us know so that we may maintain accurate information about these materials.
If you are a rights holder and are concerned that you have found material on this website for which you have not granted permission (or is not covered by a copyright exception under US copyright laws), you may request the removal of the material from our site by submitting a notice, with the elements described below, to the special.collections@nyu.edu.
Please include the following in your notice: Identification of the material that you believe to be infringing and information sufficient to permit us to locate the material; your contact information, such as an address, telephone number, and email address; a statement that you are the owner, or authorized to act on behalf of the owner, of an exclusive right that is allegedly infringed and that you have a good-faith belief that use of the material in the manner complained of is not authorized by the copyright owner, its agent, or the law; a statement that the information in the notification is accurate and made under penalty of perjury; and your physical or electronic signature. Upon receiving a notice that includes the details listed above, we will remove the allegedly infringing material from public view while we assess the issues identified in your notice.
Clerks -- Labor unions -- New York (State) -- New York; Professional employees -- Labor unions -- New York (State) -- New York; Labor unions -- Publishing -- United States; Publishers and publishing -- Employees -- Labor unions; Strikes and lockouts.; College teachers' unions -- New York (State) -- New York; Motion picture industry -- Employees -- Labor unions -- New York (State) -- New York; White collar workers -- Labor unions -- United States; Teachers' unions -- New York (State) -- New York; Museums -- Employees -- United States; Rosenstein, Maida; Brooklyn Museum; Film Forum, inc.; Solomon R. Guggenheim Museum; Transportation Alternatives (Organization); Portland Museum of Art; Brooklyn Friends School; Brooklyn Academy of Music; Hispanic Society of America; HarperCollins (Firm); American Folk Art Museum
- Series I: Papers and Audiovisual Materials, 1942-2004
  - District 65 Finances, 1980s (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - District 65 Finances, 1980s (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Political Action, 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - NYS Community Action Program, 1993-1995 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Silent Watchman/General Office, 1978-1992 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Labor Law Reform, 1993-1994 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Lobbying, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Social Issues, 1993-1995 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Substance Abuse, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Health and Safety — Video Display Units, 1980s (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Health and Safety — Video Display Units, 1980s (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Women's Issues, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Air Express International, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Withdraw! Liability, 1982-1986 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Sexual Harassment, undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Strike Info, undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Labor Laws, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Union Related Services, undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Labor Lit/Solidarity, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - NYS Dept of Labor, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Leaflets, 1980s (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - D 65 Elections, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Duty to Bargaining in Good Faith, undated (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Sexual Harassment, 1981-1983 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Health and Safety/General Info, 1983-1984 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Local 1199, 1989-1993 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - D 65 Finances, 1990-1991 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Women's Issues, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Child Care, 1992-1994 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Worker's Rights Board, 1994-1995 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Family Leave and Medical Act, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - NY Committee for Occupational Safety and Health, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Organizing, undated (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Black Lake Retreat, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Child Care, undated (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Union Programs, 1985-1992 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Union Busting, 1977-1980 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Health Care Reform, 1993-1994 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Academic Council, 1982-1985 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Local Union Press Assoc., 1995 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Conferences, 1992-1995 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Bob Califf, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Correspondence between Rudy Thomas and Don Bendinelli, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - International Union Business — UAW, 1993-1994 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - NY Committee for Occupational Safety and Health, 1990-1992 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Union Lit, 1982-1995 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - General Office/Silent Watchman, 1987-1988 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Silent Watchman/Negotations, 1991 (Box 3)
  - General Office/Silent Watchman Negotiations, 1987 (Box 3)
  - General Office/Silent Watchman Negotiations, 1991 (Box 3)
  - Silent Watchman, 1943-1981 (Box 3)
  - National Guardian/Reorg/RestRuc, 1993 (Box 3)
  - Silent Watchman and United Warehouse Employees, 1942-1984 (Box 3)
  - Silent Watchman Agreements, 1947-1993 (Box 3)
  - Brooklyn Historical Society, 1990-1991 (Box 6)
  - Long Island Historical Society, 1985-1988 (Box 6)
  - National Jewish Hospital, 1983-1992 (Box 3, Box 6)
  - National Guardian, 1946-1990 (Box 3)
  - Science and Society/Publishing, 1976-1986 (Box 6)
  - National Writers Union, 1990-1992 (Box 6)
  - National Law Journal, 1984 (Box 6)
  - Brooklyn Historical Society, 1985 (Box 6)
  - Royal Business School, 1987 (Box 6)
  - Riverside Church, 1992 (Box 6)
  - Glemby Corp. Retirements, 1990-1991 (Box 7)
  - Glemby Corp. Stress Workshop Survey, 1989 (Box 7)
  - Joseph Chinapen, 1990 (Box 7)
  - Glemby Contracts, 1985-1991 (Box 7)
  - Glemby, 1989-1991 (Box 7)
  - CBTU Convention VHS (Box 4)
  - Dr. Wyatt Tee Walker VHS (Box 4)
  - Boycott Shell VHS (Box 4)
  - Security Plan Conference VHS (Box 4)
  - Democracy At Work: Labor Looks at 1988 Presidential Candidates VHS (Box 4)
  - D 65 at Hofstra VHS (Box 4)
  - Security Plan Conference/Jim Bell VHS (Box 4)
  - Anti-Apartheid PSA VHS (Box 4)
  - Jim Bell/Hagles/Herns Fight VHS (Box 4)
  - Former Bargaining Units VHS (Box 4)
  - Club Med, 1989-1990 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Kamini Gandhi, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Job Descriptions, 1983-1989 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Layoff Severence Letters, 1983-1989 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Club Med/General, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Contracts, 1988-1990 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Club Med/Contracts, 1989-1991 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Non Traditional Employment Women (NEW), 1990-1992 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Catholic Guardian Society, 1991-1993 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - General Office/Metropolitan News Co, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Glemby, 1989-91 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - DCA Food Industries Inc, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - DCA Food Industries Contract and Index, undated (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Citizen Action, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - D 65 UAW Organizing in Non Traditional Areas, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Other Union Correspondence/Literature, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - UMWA, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Rub Sheets/Union Busting, 1976-79 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Boston University Union and Anti Union, 1970s (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Anti Union Material-Yale, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Boston Anti Union Lit, 1970s (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - List Of All Shops and Info on TOP Division, undated (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - General 65 Info, undated (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - New Tech, 1984-1985 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - TOP, 1988-1989 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Benefit Tickets, undated (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - New York Emergency Co., 1990-1993 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Women's Committee, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Yale ARB Award, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - University Organizing Contracts, 1980s (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - D 65 Health and Safety Dept of Labor Grant, 1994-1995 (Box 5, Folder 18)
- Series II: Archived Websites, March 2009-ongoing; 21 websites in 21 archived websites.
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains the main website for the Technical, Office and Professional (TOP) Union, Local 2110 and its active units. The website includes a listing of affiliated workplaces and organizing committees, workshops and classes, and collective bargaining agreements. From 2009-2012, the website had more of a focus on action and organizing campaigns, such as the 2008 presidential election, TA & RA Bargaining Rights Act, Tenement Museum Educators organizing, NYU graduate employees union recognition, UAW Gimme 5 program, Harper's Magazine organizing, Wisconsin workers solidarity, Occupy Wall Street solidarity, and contract negotiations at Columbia University, Teachers College, and Barnard College.
  From 2012 onwards the website redesigned and mostly consisted of PDFs of contracts and memoranda of agreements for the Local's workplaces. Workplaces represented over time have included the American Civil Liberties Union, Ames & Rollinson, AMSCO School Publications, Asian American Writers Workshop, Barnard College, Barnard Contingent Faculty, Bronx Museum of the Arts, Brooklyn Academy of Music, Brooklyn Friends School, Center for Reproductive Rights, Children's Museum of the Arts, Church World Service, Columbia University, DASNY: Dormitory Authority of the State of New York, GOLES: Good Old Lower East Side, HarperCollins Publishers, Harper's Magazine, Harriet Beecher Stowe Center, HFA: New York State Housing Finance Agency, ICCR: Interfaith Center on Corporate Responsibility, Mercy College, Monthly Review, Ms. Foundation for Women, Museum of Modern Art, New York, National Council of Churches, New Press, New York Civil Liberties Union, New York University & NYU Poly Graduate Assistants (GSOC-UAW), New-York Historical Society, NYSHCR: New York State Homes and Community Renewal, Pearson Longman Publishers, Rabinowitz, Boudin, Standard, Krinsky & Lieberman, P.C., Rosa Luxemburg Stiftung, Inc., SONYMA: State of New York Mortgage Agency, Stamford Advocate, State Bank of India, TCI: Technical Careers Institute, Teachers College, Tenement Museum, The New Museum of Contemporary Art, The Shed, Transportation Alternatives, Union Theological Seminary, the Village Voice, Film Forum, Brooklyn Museum, Guggenheum Museum, Studio in a School, Portland Museum of Art, Hispanic Society, Whitney Museum, MASS MoCA, Film at Lincoln Center, the Noguchi Museum, Abrams Books, the American Folk Art Museum, and the Metropolitan Museum of Art.
  In 2023, the Facebook page was added to capture materials related to unit strikes and other news.
  Websites of the union's units were also captured to document union formation and recognition, strike activities, and elections.
  Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
  Due to technical or privacy issues, archived websites may not be exact copies of the original website at the time of the web crawl. Certain file types will not be captured dependent on how they are embedded in the site. Other parts of websites that the crawler has difficulty capturing includes Javascript, streaming content, database-driven content, and highly interactive content. Full-Text searches of archived websites are available at https://archive-it.org/organizations/567.
  Accruals
  New site crawls are accrued semiannually.
  Appraisal
  Crawl was limited to domains, subdomains, and units of www.2110uaw.org in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Arrangement
  Series arranged by capture date, then alphabetically by name.
  - United Automobile Workers of America, Local 2110, March 2009-ongoing
  - BAMunion, January 2023-ongoing
  - Brooklyn Friends School Union, January 2023-ongoing
  - HarperCollins Union, January 2023-ongoing
  - Maine PMA Union, January 2023-ongoing
  - Studio in a School Union, January 2023-ongoing
  - Transportation Alternatives Union, January 2023-ongoing
  - Film Forum Union, March 2023-ongoing
  - Brooklyn Museum Union, April 2023-ongoing
  - Guggenheim Museum Union, April 2023-ongoing
  - Hispanic Society Union, April 2023-ongoing
  - Whitney Museum Union, April 2023-ongoing
  - American Folk Art Museum Union, June 2024-ongoing
  - Film at Lincoln Center Union, July 2024-ongoing
  - MASS MoCA Union, July 2024-ongoing
  - Noguchi Union, December 2024-ongoing
  - Abrams Union, April 2025-ongoing
  - Met Union, November 2025-ongoing